{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following serotypes of Salmonella does not produce H2S?", "opta": "S choleraesuis", "optb": "S paratyphi A", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the commonest species of Salmonella for causing zoonotic disease?", "opta": "S Indiana", "optb": "S newport", "optc": "S typhimurium", "optd": "S enteritidis", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following media is selective for Salmonella?", "opta": "Thiosulphate citrate bile salt agar", "optb": "Wilson and Blair's brilliant-green bismuth sulphite agar medium", "optc": "Bile salt agar", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Xylose lysine deoxycholate (XLD) agar is better selective medium than the deoxycholate citrate agar (DCA) because", "opta": "it is selective", "optb": "it imparts better growth", "optc": "it contains high salt concentration", "optd": "it is less inhibitory to S. Dysentriae and S. flexneri", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following property(ies) is/are seen in the members of family Enterobacteriaceae?", "opta": "They are catalase-positive", "optb": "They are oxidase-negative", "optc": "They ferment glucose", "optd": "They reduce nitrates to nitrites", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Dysentery may be caused by", "opta": "enteropathogenic Escherichia coli", "optb": "enteroinvasive E. coli", "optc": "enterotoxigenic E. coli", "optd": "verotoxigenic E. coli", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following(s) bacteria belong to the family Entero-bacteriaceae?", "opta": "Yersinia", "optb": "Shigella", "optc": "Salmonella", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transmission of bubonic plague is by", "opta": "rat flea", "optb": "inhalation", "optc": "ingestion", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bacteria, which is more resistant to adverse environmental conditions, is", "opta": "S sonnei", "optb": "S dysenteriae", "optc": "S flexneri", "optd": "S boydii", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reaction(s) that is/are usually positive in Escherichia coli, is/ are", "opta": "Glucose fermentation", "optb": "Indole reaction", "optc": "Methyl red reaction", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An enrichment medium for the isolation of Shigella is", "opta": "Alkaline peptone water", "optb": "Terathionate broth", "optc": "Selenite F broth", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In Widal test the significant titres for H agglutinins is", "opta": "1:50 or more", "optb": "1:100 ormore", "optc": "1:200 or more", "optd": "1:400 or more", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Heat-labile enterotoxin of Escherichia coli activates", "opta": "guanylate cyclase", "optb": "adenylate cyclase", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Heat-stable enterotoxin of Escherichia coli activates", "opta": "adenylate cyclase", "optb": "guanylate cyclase", "optc": "both of the above", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bacteria that is negative for fermentation of mannitol is", "opta": "S flexneri", "optb": "S boydii", "optc": "S dysenteriae", "optd": "S sonnei", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transmission of pneumonic plague from man to man is through", "opta": "inoculation", "optb": "ingestion", "optc": "droplet infection", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following genus belongs to family Spirochaetaceae?", "opta": "Treponema", "optb": "Spirochaeta", "optc": "Borrelia", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following bacteria is/are known as coliform bacilli?", "opta": "Escherichia", "optb": "Klebsiella", "optc": "Enterobacter", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The agent(s) which can cause plague is/are", "opta": "Yersinia pestis", "optb": "Proteus mirabilis", "optc": "Pseudomonas aeruginosa", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Salmonellae can also be killed by", "opta": "pasteurisation", "optb": "chlorination", "optc": "boiling", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sereny test is used for the detection of", "opta": "enteropathogenic Escherichia coli", "optb": "enterotoxigenic E. coli", "optc": "enteroinvasive E. coli", "optd": "verotoxigenic E. coli", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Prodigiosin (red pigment) is produced by members of genus", "opta": "Hafnia", "optb": "Enterobacter", "optc": "Serratia", "optd": "Cirobacter", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following serotypes of Salmonella can cause gastroenteritis?", "opta": "S enteritidis", "optb": "S newport", "optc": "S typhimurium", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sylvatic plague occurs in", "opta": "mice", "optb": "squirrels", "optc": "chipmunks", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Verotoxin 1 of Escherichia coli is similar to", "opta": "cholera toxin", "optb": "shiga toxin", "optc": "heat-stable enterotoxin of E. coli", "optd": "heat-labile enterotoxin of E. coli", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following determine the pathogenicity of Yersinia pestis?", "opta": "V and W antigens", "optb": "F1 envelope antigen", "optc": "Production of pigmented colonies on haemin containing media", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Enterobacter can be differentiated from Klebsiella by", "opta": "ornithine positivity", "optb": "motility", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In Yersinia pestis, capsule is best demonstrated in cultures grown at", "opta": "25\u00b0C", "optb": "29\u00b0C", "optc": "37\u00b0C", "optd": "45\u00b0C", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following can readily kill Salmonellae?", "opta": "Moist heat at 55\u00b0C for 20 min", "optb": "Moist heat at 55\u00b0C for 10 min", "optc": "Moist heat at 55\u00b0C for 30 min", "optd": "Moist heat at 55\u00b0C for 1 hr", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Traveller's diarrhea is caused by", "opta": "enteropathogenic Escherichia coli (EPEC)", "optb": "entero invasive E. coli (EIEC)", "optc": "entero toxigenic E. coli (ETEC)", "optd": "entero haemorrhagic E. coli (EHEC)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following disease is caused by Yersinia enterocolitica in man?", "opta": "Gastroenteritis", "optb": "Mesenteric lymphadenitis", "optc": "Septicaemia", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most common cause of urinary tract infection in the community is", "opta": "Klebsiella pneumoniae", "optb": "Proteus vulgaris", "optc": "Escherichia coli", "optd": "Citrobacter freundii", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bipolar staining is characteristic of", "opta": "Yersinia pestis", "optb": "Proteus mirabilis", "optc": "Pseudomonas aeruginosa", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Spirochaetes exhibit", "opta": "corkscrew-like rotatory movement", "optb": "flexion and extension motility", "optc": "translatory motion", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Species of Shigella which is predominant in India is", "opta": "S sonnei", "optb": "S dysenteriae", "optc": "S boydii", "optd": "S flexneri", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following species/subspecies of Klebsiella produce indole?", "opta": "K pneumoniae subspecies rhinoscleromatis", "optb": "K pneumoniae subspecies aerogenes", "optc": "K pneumoniae subspecies pneumoniae", "optd": "K oxytoca", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Primarily human pathogenic bacteria is/are ,", "opta": "Salmonella typhi", "optb": "S paratyphi A", "optc": "S paratyphi B", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bacteria which produce(s) \u03b2-galactosidase is/are", "opta": "Citrobacter", "optb": "Enterohacter", "optc": "Serratia", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following property(ies), shown by the organisms belong(s) to the family Enterobacteriaceae?", "opta": "They are catalase-positive", "optb": "They are oxidase-negative", "optc": "They ferment glucose", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In Widal test, the significant titre for O agglutinins is generally", "opta": "1:50 or more", "optb": "1:100 or more", "optc": "1:150 or more", "optd": "1:2.00 or more", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Selective media for the isolation of Shigella is", "opta": "Hektoen enteric agar", "optb": "Salmonella-Shigella agar", "optc": "Xylose lysine deoxycholate agar", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The technique(s), used for the assay of heat-labile enterotoxin produced by Escherichia coli, is/are", "opta": "Steroid production in Yl mouse adrenal cell culture", "optb": "Morphological changes in Chinese hamster ovary", "optc": "Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Yersinia enterocolitica and Y. pestis can be differentiated on the basis of which of the following tests?", "opta": "Decarboxylation of ornithine", "optb": "Fermentation of sucrose and cellobiose", "optc": "Motility at 22\u00b0C", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Example of the pathogenic bacteria is/are", "opta": "L biflexa", "optb": "Lparva", "optc": "Leptospira interrogans", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The media which serve(s) as enrichment media for Salmonella is/are", "opta": "Tetrathionate broth", "optb": "Brilliant green tetrathionate broth", "optc": "Selenite-F broth", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}